<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<section xml:id="C9.S16">
<title>Physical Applications</title>        
  
 
<para xml:id="C9.S16.p1">

<sentence sentence-num-in-para="1" sentence-num-in-section="1" xml:id="C9.S16.p1.s1">
Airy functions are applied in many branches of both classical and quantum physics.
</sentence>

<sentence sentence-num-in-para="2" sentence-num-in-section="2" xml:id="C9.S16.p1.s2">
The function <Math mode="inline" xml:id="C9.S16.p1.m1">\mathrm{Ai}\left(x\right)</Math> first appears as an integral in two articles by G.B. Airy on the intensity of light in the neighborhood of a caustic (Airy (1838, 1849)).
</sentence>

<sentence sentence-num-in-para="3" sentence-num-in-section="3" xml:id="C9.S16.p1.s3">
Details of the Airy theory are given invan de Hulst (1957) in the chapter on the optics of a raindrop.
</sentence>

<sentence sentence-num-in-para="4" sentence-num-in-section="4" xml:id="C9.S16.p1.s4">
See also Berry (1966, 1969).
</sentence>

</para>
 
<para xml:id="C9.S16.p2">

<sentence sentence-num-in-para="1" sentence-num-in-section="5" xml:id="C9.S16.p2.s1">
The frequent appearances of the Airy functions in both classical and quantum physics is associated with wave equations with turning points, for which asymptotic (WKBJ) solutions are exponential on one side and oscillatory on the other.
</sentence>

<sentence sentence-num-in-para="2" sentence-num-in-section="6" xml:id="C9.S16.p2.s2">
The Airy functions constitute uniform approximations whose region of validity includes the turning point and its neighborhood.
</sentence>

<sentence sentence-num-in-para="3" sentence-num-in-section="7" xml:id="C9.S16.p2.s3">
Within classical physics, they appear prominently in physical optics, electromagnetism, radiative transfer, fluid mechanics, and nonlinear wave propagation.
</sentence>

<sentence sentence-num-in-para="4" sentence-num-in-section="8" xml:id="C9.S16.p2.s4">
Examples dealing with the propagation of light and with radiation of electromagnetic waves are given inLandau and Lifshitz (1962).
</sentence>

<sentence sentence-num-in-para="5" sentence-num-in-section="9" xml:id="C9.S16.p2.s5">
Extensive use is made of Airy functions in investigations in the theory of electromagnetic diffraction and radiowave propagation (Fock (1965)).
</sentence>

<sentence sentence-num-in-para="6" sentence-num-in-section="10" xml:id="C9.S16.p2.s6">
The use of Airy function and related uniform asymptotic techniques tocalculate amplitudes of polarized rainbows can be found inNussenzveig (1992) and Adam (2002).
</sentence>

<sentence sentence-num-in-para="7" sentence-num-in-section="11" xml:id="C9.S16.p2.s7">
A quite different application is made in the study of the diffraction of sound pulses by a circular cylinder (Friedlander (1958)).
</sentence>

</para>
   
<para xml:id="C9.S16.p3">

<sentence sentence-num-in-para="1" sentence-num-in-section="12" xml:id="C9.S16.p3.s1">
In fluid dynamics, Airy functions enter several topics.
</sentence>

<sentence sentence-num-in-para="2" sentence-num-in-section="13" xml:id="C9.S16.p3.s2">
In the study of the stability of a two-dimensional viscous fluid, the flow is governed by the Orr–Sommerfeld equation (a fourth-order differential equation).
</sentence>

<sentence sentence-num-in-para="3" sentence-num-in-section="14" xml:id="C9.S16.p3.s3">
Again, the quest for asymptotic approximations that are uniformly valid solutions to this equation in the neighborhoods of critical points leads (after choosing solvable equations with similar asymptotic properties) to Airy functions.
</sentence>

<sentence sentence-num-in-para="4" sentence-num-in-section="15" xml:id="C9.S16.p3.s4">
Other applications appear in the study of instability of Couette flow of an inviscid fluid.
</sentence>

<sentence sentence-num-in-para="5" sentence-num-in-section="16" xml:id="C9.S16.p3.s5">
These examples of transitions to turbulence are presented in detail in Drazin and Reid (1981) with the problem of hydrodynamic stability.
</sentence>

<sentence sentence-num-in-para="6" sentence-num-in-section="17" xml:id="C9.S16.p3.s6">
The investigation of the transition between subsonic and supersonic of a two-dimensional gas flow leads to the Euler–Tricomi equation (Landau and Lifshitz (1987)).
</sentence>

<sentence sentence-num-in-para="7" sentence-num-in-section="18" xml:id="C9.S16.p3.s7">
An application of Airy functions to the solution of this equation is given in Gramtcheff (1981).
</sentence>

</para>
   
<para xml:id="C9.S16.p4">

<sentence sentence-num-in-para="1" sentence-num-in-section="19" xml:id="C9.S16.p4.s1">
Airy functions play a prominent role in problems defined by nonlinear wave equations.
</sentence>

<sentence sentence-num-in-para="2" sentence-num-in-section="20" xml:id="C9.S16.p4.s2">
These first appeared in connection with the equation governing theevolution of long shallow water waves of permanent form, generally called solitons, and are predicted by the Korteweg–de Vries (KdV) equation (a third-order nonlinear partial differential equation).
</sentence>

<sentence sentence-num-in-para="3" sentence-num-in-section="21" xml:id="C9.S16.p4.s3">
The KdV equation and solitons have applications in many branches of physics, including plasma physics lattice dynamics, and quantum mechanics.
</sentence>

<sentence sentence-num-in-para="4" sentence-num-in-section="22" xml:id="C9.S16.p4.s4">
(Ablowitz and Segur (1981),Ablowitz and Clarkson (1991), and Whitham (1974).)
</sentence>

</para>
 
<para xml:id="C9.S16.p5">

<sentence sentence-num-in-para="1" sentence-num-in-section="23" xml:id="C9.S16.p5.s1">
Reference to many of these applications as well as to the theory of elasticity and to the heat equation are given in Vallée and Soares (2010): a book devoted specifically to the Airy and Scorer functions and their applications in physics.
</sentence>

</para>
  
<para xml:id="C9.S16.p6">

<sentence sentence-num-in-para="1" sentence-num-in-section="24" xml:id="C9.S16.p6.s1">
An example from quantum mechanics is given in Landau and Lifshitz (1965), in which the exact solution of the Schrödinger equation for the motion of a particle in a homogeneous external field is expressed in terms of <Math mode="inline" xml:id="C9.S16.p6.m1">\mathrm{Ai}\left(x\right)</Math>.
</sentence>

<sentence sentence-num-in-para="2" sentence-num-in-section="25" xml:id="C9.S16.p6.s2">
Solutions of the Schrödinger equation involving the Airy functions are given for other potentials in Vallée and Soares (2010).
</sentence>

<sentence sentence-num-in-para="3" sentence-num-in-section="26" xml:id="C9.S16.p6.s3">
This reference provides several examples of applications to problems in quantum mechanics in which Airy functions give uniform asymptotic approximations, valid in the neighborhood of a turning point. A study of the semiclassical description of quantum-mechanical scattering is given in Ford and Wheeler (1959a, b).
</sentence>

<sentence sentence-num-in-para="4" sentence-num-in-section="27" xml:id="C9.S16.p6.s4">
In the case of the rainbow, the scattering amplitude is expressed in terms of <Math mode="inline" xml:id="C9.S16.p6.m2">\mathrm{Ai}\left(x\right)</Math> , the analysis being similar to that given originally by Airy (1838) for thecorresponding problem in optics.
</sentence>

</para>
  
<para xml:id="C9.S16.p7">

<sentence sentence-num-in-para="1" sentence-num-in-section="28" xml:id="C9.S16.p7.s1">
An application of the Scorer functions is to the problem of the uniform loading of infinite plates (Rothman (1954b, a)).
</sentence>

</para>
 
</section>
