<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<section xml:id="C7.S21">
<title>Physical Applications</title>        
           
 
<para xml:id="C7.S21.p1">

<sentence sentence-num-in-para="1" sentence-num-in-section="1" xml:id="C7.S21.p1.s1">
The error functions, Fresnel integrals, and related functions occur in a variety of physical applications.
</sentence>

<sentence sentence-num-in-para="2" sentence-num-in-section="2" xml:id="C7.S21.p1.s2">
Fresnel integrals and Cornu’s spiral occurred originally in the analysis of the diffraction of light; see Born and Wolf (1999, §8.7).
</sentence>

<sentence sentence-num-in-para="3" sentence-num-in-section="3" xml:id="C7.S21.p1.s3">
More recently, Cornu’s spiral appears in the design of highways and railroad tracks, robot trajectory planning, and computer-aided design; see Meek and Walton (1992).
</sentence>

</para>
 
<para xml:id="C7.S21.p2">

<sentence sentence-num-in-para="1" sentence-num-in-section="4" xml:id="C7.S21.p2.s1">
Carslaw and Jaeger (1959) gives many applications and points out the importance of the repeated integrals of the complementary error function <Math mode="inline" xml:id="C7.S21.p2.m1">\mathop{\mathrm{i}^{n}\mathrm{erfc}}\left(z\right)</Math>.
</sentence>

<sentence sentence-num-in-para="2" sentence-num-in-section="5" xml:id="C7.S21.p2.s2">
Fried and Conte (1961) mentions the role of <Math mode="inline" xml:id="C7.S21.p2.m2">w\left(z\right)</Math> in the theory of linearized waves or oscillations in a hot plasma; <Math mode="inline" xml:id="C7.S21.p2.m3">w\left(z\right)</Math> is called the plasma dispersion function or Faddeeva (or Faddeyeva) function; see Faddeeva and Terent’ev (1954).Ng and Geller (1969) cites work with applications from atomic physics and astrophysics.
</sentence>

<sentence sentence-num-in-para="3" sentence-num-in-section="6" xml:id="C7.S21.p2.s3">
Efficient algorithms for computing the Faddeeva (or Faddeyeva) function are discussed in Wells (1999), a paper frequently cited in the astrophysics literature.
</sentence>

</para>

  
<para xml:id="C7.S21.p3">

<sentence sentence-num-in-para="1" sentence-num-in-section="7" xml:id="C7.S21.p3.s1">
Voigt functions <Math mode="inline" xml:id="C7.S21.p3.m1">\mathsf{U}\left(x,t\right)</Math> , <Math mode="inline" xml:id="C7.S21.p3.m2">\mathsf{V}\left(x,t\right)</Math> , can be regarded as the convolution of a Gaussian and a Lorentzian, and appear when the analysis of light (or particulate) absorption (or emission) involves thermal motion effects.
</sentence>

<sentence sentence-num-in-para="2" sentence-num-in-section="8" xml:id="C7.S21.p3.s2">
These applications include astrophysics, plasma diagnostics, neutron diffraction, laser spectroscopy, and surface scattering.
</sentence>

<sentence sentence-num-in-para="3" sentence-num-in-section="9" xml:id="C7.S21.p3.s3">
See Mitchell and Zemansky (1961, §IV.2),Armstrong (1967), and Ahn et al. (2001).
</sentence>

<sentence sentence-num-in-para="4" sentence-num-in-section="10" xml:id="C7.S21.p3.s4">
Dawson’s integral appears in de-convolving even more complex motional effects; seePratt (2007).
</sentence>

</para>
 
</section>
